Rishabh Chaurasia

rishabhchaurasia102000@gmail.com+91~8928704876

Profile Summary

MCA student at Graphic Era University with a strong motivation for technology. Experienced in web development, Python, and C programming. Excellent communication skills, decision-making, and mentoring. Driven to use technology for real-world problem-solving and beneficial change.

Education

Master of Computer Applications (MCA)

Graphic Era (Deemed to be University), Dehradun

Aug 2023 - Present

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Shree L.R. Tiwari College of Arts, Commerce, and Science

Aug 2018 - Jun 2021

Experience

• Technical Support Engineer – Hewlett-Packard (HP)

Jan 2022 - May 2023

- Resolved over 1,000 technical issues, ensuring 99% customer satisfaction.
- Optimized hardware, software, and network performance.
- Client Issue Resolution Specialist ICICI Prudential

Jun 2021 - Dec 2021

- Managed and resolved client inquiries and concerns with precision.
- Enhanced customer satisfaction and ensured seamless policy administration.

Projects

- Stock Market Analysis and Forecasting using Deep Learning
 - Developed predictive models using deep learning techniques to analyze and forecast stock market trends.
- Chatbot using Python
 - Designed and implemented a chatbot leveraging Python for intelligent interaction and problem-solving.

Skills

Professional Skills:

- MySQL, Data Structures , Pl-SQL
- \bullet Web Development, C , Python

Personal Skills:

- Self-drive, Organized, Structured
- Communication, Problem Solving

Interests

Playing chess, Football

Languages

- English Proficient
- Hindi Native

Personal Details

Name: Rishabh Chaurasia Contact No: +91 8928704876

Email: rishabhchaurasia102000@gmail.com Current Location: Dehradun, Uttarakhand Permanent Address: Mumbai, Maharashtra